我们,是水晶
♪ We ♪ are the crystal
战士
♪ gems
我们总能拯救世界
♪ we'll always save the day
如果你认为我们不行
♪ and if you think we can't, ♪
我们总能找到方法
♪ we'll always find a way
这就是为什么这个世界
♪ that's why the people
的人
♪ of this world
相信
♪ believe in
石榴
♪ Garnet
紫晶
♪ Amethyst
和珍珠
♪ and Pearl
和史蒂文!
and Steven!
下雨之时
欢迎关注微博@UUU字幕组，获取最新熟肉信息！
出品
presisco
翻译
零玖/presisco
校对
presisco
特效
压制
presisco
标题取自俗语"when it rains, it pours."（要下雨就下大）
快开门,橄榄石!
Open the door, Peridot.
如果"融合簇"真的置我们于危险之中
If this "cluster" is putting us in danger,
你得告诉我们那是什么,这样我们才能阻止它
you need to tell us what it is so we can stop it.
不!我讨厌你们
No! I hate you.
我才不告诉你们融合簇的任何信息呢
I'm not telling you anything about the cluster.
哦,搞毛
Oh, come on.
那是像一大团,呃,即食麦片吗?
Is it like a big, uh, hunk of granola?
什么是即食麦片?
What's granola?
我很确定那不是即食麦片
I'm sure it's not granola.
听着,橄榄石,
Now, Peridot,
我确定我们能达成一定共识
I'm sure we can reach some sort of agreement.
也许我们来做个交易?
Perhaps a trade is in order?
哦,真好
Oh, sure.
为什么不给我
Why don't you just give me back
我的腿部和臂部增强器?
my leg enhancements and my arm attachments
外加我的显示屏和日志和所有的信息?
with my screen and my log and all my information.
哦,等等,你毁了它们!
Oh, wait, you destroyed them!
所以,不,我不认为我们能达成某种共识!
So, no, I don't think we can reach some sort of agreement!
好吧,橄榄石,你可以转身了
Okay, Peridot, you can turn around now.
很抱歉打断你们的审讯
Sorry for interrupting your interrogation.
不要担心,史蒂文
Don't worry about it, Steven.
我发誓,橄榄石随时都会招供的
I swear, Peridot is gonna crack any second now.
我永远不会像你们招供的,
I'll never crack for the likes of you,
你们这群...水晶草包!
you...Crystal clods.
哦～,你的草包们可就在门口,你个小-
Ooh, I got your clods right here, you little --
等等,珍珠
hold on, Pearl.
如果她不愿意提供任何帮助的话
If she's not gonna be of any help.
让我们自己来调查这件事
Let's investigate this thing on our own.
我会跟你一起做的
I'll come with you.
对不起,史蒂文
Sorry, Steven.
我们需要你呆在家里
We're gonna need you to stay here
看管我们的...贵宾
and keep an eye on our...Guest.
真的?
Really?
对,确保她不会搞幺蛾子
Yeah. Make sure she doesn't try anything.
别担心
Don't worry.
她失去肢端增强器后没什么威胁
She's harmless without her limb enhancers
我才不是毫无威胁呢!
I'm not harmless!
哦,给我闭嘴!
Oh, hush up!
噢,史蒂文!
Oh, Steven!
还有一件事我得提
There's one more thing I have to mention.
是什么?
What is it?
我爱你,拜拜
I love you. Bye.
待会见
See ya later.
嗯～
Mm.
你得知道,她们走了,你现在可以出来了
They left, you know. You can come out now.
不,我-我喜欢在里面
No. I-I like it in here.
好吧
Okay.
喔,看来真要下雨了
Wow. It's really coming down.
开始了!
It's happening!
什么?
What?
-融合簇!
-The cluster!
真的?
Really?
还有什么能制造那么恐怖的-
What else could be making that horrible --
啊啊!它在内部拍击着地球
Aah! It's pounding on the earth from the inside.
这是世界末日了
This is it. This is the end of the world.
哦,那只是闪电而已
Oh, that's just thunder.
什么?
What?
没错,一切都还正常
Yeah, everything is fine.
那只是闪电,跟着雨一起出现
It's just thunder. It happens when it rains.
呃...蛤?
Eh...Huh?
你不知道雨?
You don't know about rain?
离开我的屏幕,我什么都不知道
I don't know anything without my screen.
这没什么
It's okay.
看,假设汤是大海
Here, pretend this soup is the ocean.
当太阳加热汤时,
When the sun warms it up,
水被蒸发,形成云
the water evaporates into clouds,
就如同这蒸汽
like this steam.
而当云变得非常重时,就开始下雨了
And when the clouds get really heavy, it rains.
所以滚烫的液体从天上倾泻而下?
So scalding liquid pours down from the sky?
不,不,只是水而已,那伤害不了你
No, no, it's just water. It can't hurt you.
来,为什么不让我给你展示一下呢?
Here, why don't I just show you.
史蒂文,等等!
Steven, wait!
来吧!
Come on!
看,我很好,这只是水而已
Look, I'm okay. It's just water.
这只是地球上发生的正常现象
This is just something that happens on earth.
很凉爽吧?
Isn't it cool?
爽!
Yeah!
太好了,你做到了!
Yeah, you did it!
你感觉怎么样?是不是很凉爽?
What do you think? Isn't it cool?
凉爽
Cool.
那真有趣
That was fun.
哈?
Huh?
那...凑合吧
It was...Something.
嗯...
Hmm.
呃...
Uh...
嗯...
Mm...
史蒂文?
Steven?
嗯?
Hm?
我要宣布一件事情
I'm going to say something.
谢谢你
Thank you.
呃...为什么?
Uh...What for?
因为你向我解释了"雨"
For explaining this "rain" business to me.
哦,没关系
Oh, no problem.
有关系,你是个非常有智慧的生物
Yes. You're a much more intelligent creature
相比于我的预期的话
than I initially thought.
呃,那挺好啊
Uh, that's good.
没错
Yes.
有很多...用处,相比那些草包
Much more...Useful than those clods.
史蒂文,我决定了!
Steven, I've made up my mind!
决定什么?
About what, exactly?
我决定和你分享一些信息
I've decided to share some information with you.
啊,我早知道你用了我的牙刷
Ah, I know you use my toothbrush.
不-不
N-no.
呃,没错
Well, yes.
但这是关于融合簇的
But it's about the cluster.
你招了
You cracked.
我才没招呢!
I haven't cracked!
等等,你得告诉宝石人们,她们得知道
Wait, you have to tell the gems. They need to know this.
不,我才不要和她们说呢
No, I don't want to talk to them.
你是我需要的唯一的一个
You're the only one I need.
我可以现在告诉你,但我缺少材料
I could show you now, but I have nothing.
我的臂部增强件,我的手指,我的屏幕,我的日志-
My arm attachments, my fingers, my screen, my log --
都没了
it's all gone.
但我所有的直到652的日志都还在
But all of my logs up to date 652 still exist.
备份在主幼儿园的第五切面内
Backed up in facet 5 of the prime kindergarten.
你想让我带你去幼儿园?
You want me to take you to the kindergarten?
我不确定...
I don't know.
史蒂文,你不想了解融合簇吗?
Steven, don't you want to know about the cluster?
嗯...好吧
Mm...Okay.
我们可以去幼儿园
We can go to the kindergarten.
哦,太好了!
Oh, yes!
但...
But...
不好,有诈
No, a catch.
好吧,你的要求是什么?
Fine. What are your demands?
你得一直抓着我的手
You're gonna have to hold my hand the whole time.
看,我们到了
Well, here we are.
好吧,太棒了,我们走
Okay, great. Let's go.
这里每次来都变得更糟
This place just gets worse every time I come here.
我知道,这里的管理太糟糕了
I know. It's been so poorly managed.
当你第一次孵化出来时
It must have been in way better shape
这里要好很多吧?
when you first emerged.
孵化?
Emerged?
没错,你算是某种石英,对吧?
Yeah, you're some kind of Quartz, right?
你一定是在这里制造的
You must have been made here.
呃...我是源自我的妈妈和爸爸
Uh...I came from my mom and dad.
那是某种石头吗?或者另一个星球?
Are those some kind of rocks? Or another planet?
并不
Nope.
我爸爸来自地球,而我妈妈是宝石人
My dad's from earth, but my mom's a gem.
你算是某种混血?这怎么可能呢?
You're some sort of hybrid? How is that possible?
答案在一个故事里,而我将它命名为
The answer to that is a story I like to call
"玫瑰和格雷格的罗曼史"
"the ballad of Rose and Greg."
"the ballad of Rose and Greg"出自披头士的歌名"The Ballad of John and Yoko"
我不在乎
I don't care.
我们赶紧去控制室吧
Let's just hurry to the control room.
你确定那里安全?
You sure this is safe?
上次我去那时,
The last time I was here,
那里有一堆融合怪物
there were a bunch of fusion monsters.
没错,我之前在检查它们的进展
Yes, I was checking their progress.
那些是用来干嘛的?
What's the deal with those things?
当很明显地球不再是可用的殖民地时,
When it became clear that the earth was no longer a viable colony,
母世界决定将它用于其它方面-
homeworld decided to use it for something else --
一系列的实验
a series of experiments.
一个宝石终极武器
A gem geo-weapon.
噢,你参与了吗?
Oh, did you help?
并没有
Negative.
我没好运生在那个时候
I wasn't lucky enough to be around for that.
但我浏览了好几百年的报告呢
But I read over a few hundred years of reports.
你要来这里,对吧?
This is where you need to be, right?
没错,我得移开这个面板
Yes. I'm going to have to remove this panel
然后做点工作恢复这间屋子的能量供应,
and do a bit of work to restore power to this room,
所以...我能把手收回来吗?
so...Can I have my hand back now?
好吧,但呆在我能看见的地方
Okay, but stay where I can see you.
完了
It's over.
我没法向你展示任何东西,咱们回吧
I can't show you anything. Let's go back.
介意我试试吗?
Mind if I try?
上啊
Go ahead.
随你便
Knock yourself out.
喔!
Whoa!
走你
There you go.
好吧
All right.
在这里...
This over here...
虽然算不上完美,但暂时够用了
It's not perfect, but it'll do for now.
别呀
Come on.
怎么了,小橄?
What's up, dot?
"What's up, Dot?"出自"What's up, Doc?"，兔八哥的习惯用语
我够不到-
I can't quite reach the --.
寻求帮助没什么不好,你要知道
It's okay to ask for help, you know.
可以了
I had it.
这些是人工融合的早期尝试
These are the early attempts at artificial fusion.
那真是好多的宝石碎片啊
That's a lot of gem shards.
我们原来在这里培养它们
We were growing them here at this very site.
但这些只是最终产物的原型而已
But these were just prototypes for the final product,
一个单独的巨大人工融合体
a singular giant artificial fusion
由几百万的宝石碎片组成
comprised of millions of gem shards --
融合簇
the cluster.
橄榄石,你是说现在有个
Peridot, you're saying there's a giant mutant gem
地球那么大的突变宝石人在脚下?
the size of the earth under us right now?
哦,不
Oh, no.
当它最终成型时,比地球可大多了
When it forms it'll be much, much bigger than the earth.
现在它潜伏在地球核心,慢慢孵化
Right now it lies dormant, incubating in the earth's core.
但当它孵化并产生物质形态时,
But when it emerges and takes its physical form,
它会摧毁地球
it will destroy the planet.
原型已经开始孵化了
The prototypes are already emerging.
融合簇则是下一个
The cluster is next.
如果我们不能离开这个星球,我们就得阻止融合簇
If we can't get off this planet, we've got to stop the cluster.
我之前觉得这不可行,但我们现在有机会了
I thought it'd be impossible, but now we have a chance.
是什么?
What is it?
你呀,史蒂文!
It's you, Steven!
现在你出现了,我们就可以开始工作了
Now that you're filled in, we can get to work.
呃...我怎么提供帮助呢?
Uh...How am I supposed to help?
其实,你已经有了我们所需的所有信息
Well, you have all the information we need
有关于地球和它飘忽不定的行为的信息
about earth and its erratic behavior.
将那与我对融合簇丰富的了解相结合,
Put that together with my expansive knowledge of the cluster,
我们也许就能阻止它
and we just might be able to stop it.
不,橄榄石,我不认为你想到点子上了
No, Peridot, I don't think you get it.
只因为我了解云的原理,
Just because I know how clouds work,
不意味着我知道怎么阻止
doesn't mean I know how to stop
一个在地球中央的巨大突变体
a giant mutant in the center of the earth.
另外,我知道云和雨的唯一原因
Besides, the only reason I know anything about clouds and rain
是我爸爸告诉我了
is because my dad told me.
你说的是什么?
What are you talking about?
我原来非常害怕闪电,
I used to be really scared of thunderstorms,
像你一样
just like you.
然后我爸爸解释了雨之类的现象是如何发生的,
Then dad explained how rain and all that stuff works,
然后我再也没怕过雨了
then I wasn't scared of rain anymore.
那么,我确定你还有其他的
Well, I'm sure you have other knowledge
有关于这个星球如何运作的知识
about how this planet works.
当然,但那些中没有能帮到我们的
Sure, but none of it's gonna help us.
如果我们想要阻止融合簇的话,
If we want to stop this cluster thing,
我们就需要水晶战士的帮助
we'll need help from The Crystal Gems.
我说过我不需要她们!
I said I don't need them!
我们只要传送回我的卫生间就好,
Let's just warp me back to the bathroom,
或者随便你怎么叫的,然后让我们解决这个
or whatever you call it, and we'll take care of this.
如果情况真的变得非常遭,
If it looks really bad,
那么我们只需要向这个爸爸寻求帮助,对不对?
then we can just ask this dad for help, right?
咦!那是什么?
Yipe! What was that?
哦,不!宝石突变体!
Oh, no! Gem mutants!
呀!
Yaah!
做点什么啊!
Do something!
我在做啊
I am doing something.
做点有用的!
Something useful!
呃,咱们跑吧
Uh, let's run.
来这里
Over here.
不,那个方向
No, the other way.
不,不是那里
No, not there.
啊!
Aah!
咱们跑去这个角落吧
Let's run into this corner.
哦,不!
Oh, no!
我们被困在角落里了!
We're cornered!
啊!
Aah!
啊!你能摧毁它吗?
Aah! Can't you destroy it?
不,这是我自己能做的全部了
No, this is all I can do on my own.
呀....
Yaah...
就这样了,我们完蛋了
That's it. We are finished.
坚持住,史蒂文
Hang on, Steven.
宝石人们!
It's the gems!
紫晶的招式出自索尼克的招牌动作
石榴的招式与《任天堂全明星大乱斗》中皮卡丘的“雷击”招式类似
橄榄石,我们没法
Peridot, there's no way
只靠自己阻止这个在地球内的东西
we can stop this thing in the earth on our own.
我们需要水晶战士的帮助
We need the help of The Crystal Gems.
史蒂文,你还好吗?
Steven, are you all right?!
让开,史蒂文
Move aside, Steven.
橄榄石?
Peridot?!
你们两个在这干嘛?
What are you two doing here?!
史蒂文,我记得我告诉你要看住她
Steven, I thought I told you to keep an eye on her.
我知道,但-
I know, but --
他只是从犯
he did what he was told.
好吧
All right.
听着,你们这群草-
Listen up, you clo--
水晶战士
Crystal gems.
我决定了
I've made up my mind.
我有些关于融合簇的东西要告诉你们
I have something to tell you about the cluster.
我认为我非常卑微
♪ I always thought I might be bad ♪
现在我已确定
♪ now I'm sure that it's true
因,你如此完美
♪ 'cause I think you're so good ♪
而我却丝毫不如
♪ and I'm nothing like you